Guide to the Arthur L. Schawlow Papers SC0554
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1998-275
  - “Five Year Plan” – Physics Dep-t (Box 142)
  - Andrew Gemant Award Materials, 1988-1989 (Box 143)
  - ILC Technology, Inc., 1986 (Box 143)
  - ILC Hawthorne, May 14, 1985 (Box 143)
  - Laserscope, 1985 - present (Box 143)
  - Laser Safety (Box 143)
  - Optical Society of America, 1985-1992 (Box 143)
  - Newtek (Box 143)
  - Pew Science Program (Box 144)
  - Precision Laser Machining (Box 144)
  - Technology Center, Sept. 1988 (Box 144)
  - TIAA / CREF (Retirement Fund) (Box 144)
  - Charles H. Townes Science Center (Box 144)
  - Marquis Who’s Who Advisory Board (1984 – present) (Box 144)
  - Opacitrac, Manual for Operation, Sept. 1991 (Box 144)
  - Communication Pictures (Box 144)
  - Schawlow, Helen, “Prisons and Visions: Pierre Unik’s Journey from Surrealism into Marxism” (Box 144)
  - ILC Technology, Inc. (Box 145)
  - 9th Marconi Fellowship Com. Mtg., Sept. 10, 1982 (Box 145)
  - 2708/2716 Erom Board Instruction Manual Issued Sept. 1972 (Box 145)
  - Altair Basic (Box 145)
  - Zeeman Effect (Box 145)
  - Summer Davis, Univ. of California, 11.26.1985 (Box 145)
  - Heuristics Inc., 1979-1980 (Box 145)
  - Foreword to the Collected Papers of Robert Hofstadler by Robert Herman (Box 145)
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 145)
  - Miscellaneous photos etc. (Box 146)
  - Laser History Project, 1983-1984 (Box 146)
  - Laserscope (Box 146)
  - Lasertechnics, Albuquerque, April 1-2, 1983 (Box 146)
  - Lasertechnics, 1983-1984 (Box 147)
  - Vector Technology Int’l and misc. (Box 147)
  - Wright Technology (Box 147)
  - Paul Stewart (Box 147)
  - Cyrus B. Comstock Award, 1983 (Box 147)
  - Davisson-Germer Prize Committee (Box 147)
  - Lasag A.G., 1976 (Box 147)
  - R.R.Donnelley Sons & Co, 1975 (Box 147)
  - Misc. files (Box 147)
  - R.R.Donnelley Sons & Co, 1975 (cont’d) - 1976 (Box 148)
  - Temple Grandin, “My Experiences as an Autistic Child and Review of Selected Literature” (Box 148)
  - Autism brochures (Box 148)
  - Autism files, Oct. 1981 – Feb. 1982 (Box 148)
  - Autism files, March 1982 – March 1984 (Box 149)
  - Project – O.P.E.N., Oct. 1982 - present (Box 149)
  - Lithium (Box 149)
  - Creative Alternatives Fundraising Dinner, Nov. 20, 1982 (Hughson, California) (Box 149)
  - Tennessee [?] “ARC” - Book (Box 149)
  - Computers for Autistic People, Arthur L. Schawlow (Box 149)
  - Never Too Late – Communication with Autistic Adults. Aurelia T. Schawlow & Arthur L. Schawlow in Proceedings of the National Society for Children and Adults with Autism (N.S.A.C.), July 1985 (Box 149)
  - Autism, clippings, Oct. 1981 - present (Box 149)
  - Autistic Society Files, Feb. 1-4, 1982 (Box 150)
  - "Our Son: The Endless Search for Help” by Aurelia T. and Arthur L. Schawlow (Box 150)
  - Autism files, April 1984 – Oct. 1985 (Box 150)
  - N.S.A.C. Annual Conference, Los Angeles, July 12, 1985 (Box 150)
  - Autism Center – W. Virginia, Sept. 20-21, 1985 (Box 150)
  - Misc. files (Box 150)
  - Autism files, Nov. 1985 – Nov. 1986; 1988; Jan.-Feb. 1989 (Box 151)
  - Bonnet, Philip, March 1986 (Box 151)
  - L.A. Area Board, Los Angeles, June 6, 1986 (Box 151)
  - Paradise Post, August 22, 1986 (Box 151)
  - Misc. files (Box 151)
  - ITX Laboratories STIM Project (Box 152)
  - California Vocations (Box 152)
  - Canon Communicator (Box 152)
  - Autism files, May 1989 (Box 152)
  - Artie and related material (Box 152)
  - N.S.A.C., July 10-13, 1985 (Box 152)
  - Autistic Info etc. (Box 152)
  - Art (Box 152)
  - Misc. files (Box 152)
  - Physics 161 Lecture notes 1980/81 (Box 153)
  - Physics 161 Lecture notes 1982/83 (Box 153)
  - Physics 161 Lecture notes 1983/84 (Box 153)
  - Physics 161 Intermediate Optics, 1985/86 [grade reports] (Box 153)
  - Physics 23 1982/83: Problem sets & solutions, exams, and other information (Box 154)
  - Physics 23 1982/83 Supplement: ASSU Notes (Box 154)
  - Physics 23 1983/84: Problem sets & solutions, exams, and other information (Box 154)
  - Physics 23 1983/84: Lecture Notes (Box 154)
  - Physics 23 1984/85: Problem sets & solutions, exams, and other information (Box 155)
  - Physics 23 Exams 1972-1988 (Box 155)
  - Physics 23 1982/83: Lecture notes (Box 155)
  - Physics 23 Electricity and Optics, Winter 1984/85: Experiments (Box 155)
  - Physics 23 1985/86: Problem sets & solutions, exams, and other information (Box 155)
  - Physics 23 1986/87: Problem sets & solutions, exams, and other information (Box 156)
  - Physics 23 1987/88: Problem sets & solutions, exams, and other information (Box 156)
  - Physics 161 Lecture notes 1985/86 (Box 156)
  - Physics 161 Exams and grades 1987/88 (Box 157)
  - Errata for Principles of Nonlinear Optics by Y. R. Shen (1986) (Box 157)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1999-052
  - Schawlow, "Research and the Growth of New Industries" (Box 1)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-1999-242
  - Amplifying with Atoms, typescript drafts, 1965-66 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1949-54 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence (Dieter Röss), 1997 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, Aage Bohr, 1950-51 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Record of phone calls (3 notebooks), 1964-88 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2002-200
  - Patents (Box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Patents (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Patent 4,052,129 Oct. 4, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Laser Patent ‘58 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Patent: Digital Wavemeter (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Patent: ALS/Kowalski (July 1976) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - HEPL Administrative Com. 1966-67 – Present (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Laser Industry Association (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Laser Eraser [New] 1971 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Al Braun – and Correspondence: Engineering + Patent, etc. (1965-1967) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Al Braun and Correspondence: Engineering and Patent, etc. 1968- (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Wavemeter (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Laser Technology At Stanford Booklet (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Laser Eraser (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Erasing Samples (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Patent File (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Saturation Absorption Experiments (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Jones, Michieal (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Image Intensifiers (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Jack Sarfatti (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Laser Photographs (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Letters from Steve Lavine 1980s (some relate to the “Bix?” audio tapes below) (Box 1)
  - BIX? From S. Lavine 3 (reel), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - BIX?, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - BIX? From S. Lavine July 1988 (Wabash Trio, Moonlight Revellers, Betty Boop Cartoons), 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Convention Recorders: Dr. Robert K. Jarvik, Capt. Grace Hopper, Dr. William C. DeCries, Herschel Walker, Dr. Edward Teller, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Convention Recorders: Hobie Alter, Gene Autry, Mayor Andrew Young, Alan Derehowitz [some of these were crossed out and may not be part of what's recorded], 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Convention Recorders: Dr. David Hubel, Joe Paterno, Jim Davis, Sister Antonia Brenner, 1 audiocassette(s) (Box 1)
  - Videorecordings
    - Nobel Awards Ceremony 1981, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 2)
    - Nobel Awards Panel Discussion 1981, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 2)
    - “Laser: A Light Fantastic”, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 2)
    - Transcription of Gerry’s tape; Roald Hoffmann; Part 4, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 2)
    - Transcription of Gerry’s tape; Roald Hoffmann; Part 3, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 2)
    - Unlabeled beta videocassette recording; possible blank tape (Box 2)
    - Science In Action: The Scientist 1965, 1 videotape(s) (u-matic) (Box 2)
  - Motion Picture Films
    - “After Hours” Show No. 21 KINE No. 13P5460; Date Recorded: March 27, 1963; Instructions: at Science Museum, Boston (Box Reel 1)
    - “Science In Action: Scientist”, 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box Reel 2)
    - “The 21st Century: The Laser: A Light Fantastic”; Color, 25 minutes; 9/10/67; CBS News, CBS Films Inc., 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box Reel 3)
    - Canadian Schools: “Frontiers in Science: Lasers”; CBUT Film 1968; Color, 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box Reel 4)
    - “Introduction To Lasers” (Color); No. 3175; Encyclopaedia Brittanica Educational Corporation; ~25 minutes, 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box Reel 5)
    - “Laser – The Light of the Future”; Prism Productions, 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box Reel 6)
    - “Visionaries”; Movielab Inc.; Rec’d 8/1/73, 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box Reel 7)
    - “Terra Nova” by Zoltan Meszaros; May 1972; Print #1, 1 film reel(s) (16mm) (Box Reel 8)
  - Introduction to Laser Technology, produced by Maser Optics, 89 Brighton Avenue, Boston, 1 phonograph record (LP)
    General note
    filed in SC LPs Box 1
- Additional Material, Accession ARCH-2006-232
  - Calendar [Cap and Gown Stanford Calendar], 1963 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Daily record of letters received and sent, Vol. I, March 1962-December 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Daily record of letters received and sent, Vol. II, January 1966-May 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)